Guide to the Francis Valentine Keesling Papers, 1906-1957
Department of Special Collections
Francis Valentine Keesling Papers,
1906-1957
Special Collections M0100
Francis Valentine Keesling
33 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mr. Keesling, 1953 and 1957
Biography
1877, Feb. 17 born San Jose, Calif.; son of Francis Marion and Mary (Nunez) Keesling.
1898 A.B. Stanford. First president of class of '98, editor-in-chief '98 Quad, baseball manager for season of '98. Member of Philolexian Literary Society, Sigma Nu fraternity, Phi Delta Phi legal fraternity, and Skull and Snakes Honor Society.
1898 admitted to California Bar, practiced in San Francisco (retired 1953), July - entered law office of Crothers and Crothers (George E. and Thomas G.) - survey legislative candidates for '98 for adoption of amendment to state constitution permitting exemption of such foundation trusts as Stanford from taxation (passed 1901).
1901-1909 member National Guard of California, retired as major. Special board which re-wrote Calif. Military law to conform to federal; commanding artillery batallion San Francisco fire 1906.
1903, Nov. 19 married Haidee Grau - 4 children
1906-1908 regent Sigma Nu fraternity
1908-1909 attorney for General John A. Koster, auditor of San Francisco.
1910 Republican candidate for lieutenant-governor of California
1910-1938 vice-president and general counsel West Coast Life Insurance Co.
1914 Republican candidate for governor of California
1914-1916 chairman Republican State Central Committee of California
1915-1916 chairman legal section, American Life Convention
1916 & 1924 delegate to Republican National Convention
1917 Mason 33 - Grand Master of California
1917-1921 participated in every Liberty Loan Drive during World War I in executive capacity. On general executive committee and other committees of Community Chest
1919 & 1929-1930 president Stanford Alumni Association
1927-1928 chairman executive committee Association of Life Insurance Counsel
1928-1929 governor Bar Association of San Francisco
1928-1929 member committee of Bar examiners State Bar of California
1929-1930 board of governors State Bar of California
1929-1937 a director of Golden Gate Bridge and Highway District and chairman of building committee
1929-1931 vice-president Association of Life Insurance Counsel
1930 member San Francisco Board of Freeholders and chairman of drafting committee which wrote the 1931 Charter of the city and county, conducted campaign which resulted in its adoption.
1930-1933 member executive committee American Life Convention
1931-1933 president Association of Life Insurance Counsel
1931-1933 president Bar Association of San Francisco
1932-1933 president Stanford Law Society
1933-1934 president American Life Convention
1936-1942 president San Francisco Y.M.C.A.
1936-1942 chairman California Statewide Committee on Reorganization of State Government (or on Taxation and Cost of Government) known as the Interim Committee of 25
1936-1942 member board of governors Stanford Associates
1938-1949 president and director West Coast Life Insurance Co. and general counsel
1941-1942 special assistant to Attorney General of the United States Hearing officer of Northern District of California on appeals of conscientious objectors
1941-1942 organized U.S.O. Council in San Francisco, first chairman
1941 or -42 to 1947 member council National Municipal League
1941 quarterly chairman Commonwealth Club (S.F.)
1942 board of directors San Francisco Y.M.C.A.
1942-1946 chairman Civilian Council for Officer Procurement United States Navy
1942-1947 president California Insurance Federation
1943 Grand Treasurer Masons Grand Lodge, California
1943 chairman of campaign committee - Roger Lapham for mayor of San Francisco
1943-1947 member board of governors Commonwealth Club
1944-1947 chairman San Francisco Charter Revision Committee
1945-1946 director San Francisco Bay Area Council, chairman executive committee
1946-1947 member executive committee San Francisco Bay Area Council
1946- member State (California) Committee on Intergovernmental
1947 executive committee Commonwealth Club
1949-1953 chairman of the board West Coast Life Insurance Co.
1949 director Better Business Bureau of San Francisco
1963, September 25 died.
Scope and Content
The Keesling Papers consist of correspondence, diaries, notebooks, drafts of speeches and articles, reports, minutes of meetings, newspaper and magazine clippings, maps and blueprints, circular and form letters, political flyers, etc., pamphlets, annotated government documents, promotional brochures, miscellaneous printed material, and some financial and legal papers. They span the years 1906-1957, though very little material is found after 1953. The scope of the subject matter is tremendous. The political series contains a number of topics of particular interest. Most notable perhaps is that the material from 1910-1920 on local, state (California), and national Republican political campaigns. Keesling was a "regular" Republican, one of the few whose papers are extant, and greatly opposed to Hiram Johnson and the Progressives. The active part played by Keesling in California politics at this time and the scarcity of the original material by those holding similar views make this collection quite unique. The picture of this split in the California Republican party has been very one-sided in favor of the Progressives simply because of the lack of material supporting the opposition. In addition to the Hughes campaign, the Coolidge, Hoover, Willkie, Dewey, and Eisenhower Presidential campaigns are also covered. The many state and local campaigns, their candidates and issues, are represented by even more material. Other papers refer to world affairs, foreign policy, war, Communism and related movements, patriotic organizations, labor, legal matters, insurance business, government and governmental procedures, economic affairs, education and social and charitable organizations. The second series relates to the San Francisco Charter of 1931. This material is quite complete and includes Keesling's booklet on the subject and some later papers on amendments and revision. The Interim Committee of Twenty five on State Reorganization, the third series, is also a rich research source. The fourth series is on the Golden Gate Bridge and Highway District and the construction of the bridge. This is quite a complete account especially for the Building Committee from 1929 to 1937. Some, but not all, of this material was used as the basis for a doctoral dissertation in 1958. The last two series are quite small. One recounts the San Francisco earthquake and fire of 1906 through newspaper clippings and Keesling's orders and report as an officer of the National Guard and active participant in rescue and patrol work. The other contains miscellaneous material on or related to Stanford University. This collection, in addition to being of general historical interest, would seem to form a very solid base for a good biography of Keesling. It covers almost all of his activities and interests within the time span of the papers. His very frank and uninhibited correspondence reveals his personality and opinions very clearly. Of the correspondents in these papers, many number among the politically and socially prominent on local, state and national levels. Others, not so well known, are important to this collection because of the content and size of their correspondence.
Access Terms
Agnew, Frank J.; Ammann, Othmar Hermann, 1879-1965.; Arnold, Ralph, 1875-; Beek, Joseph A.; Booth, Willis H., 1874-; Boynton, Albert E.; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Carrere, John F.; Clark, Elmer Talmadge, 1886-; Coolidge, Dane, 1873-1940; Drury, Aubrey, 1891-1959.; Ferguson, Howard, 1908-; Flint, Motley H.; Griffenhagen, Edwin Oscar, 1886-; Halleck, Charles A., 1900-; Hanna, Byron C., 1887-; Hays, Will H., 1879-; Hodges, Lauder.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Johnson, Charles G., 1880-; Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945.; Jordan, Frank C., 1860-; Kahn, Julius, 1861-1924.; Keesling, Francis V. (Francis Valentine), 1877-1963.; Kenny, Robert Walker, 1901-; Kirkwood, Marion Rice, 1887-; Knight, Goodwin J. (Goodwin Jess), 1896-1970.; Knowland, Joseph Russell, 1873-; Knowland, William F., 1908-; Koster, Frederick J., 1868-; Kuchel, Thomas H., 1910-; Leavey, H. Harold, 1906-; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959.; Martin, Irving.; Martin, Joseph W., 1884-; Merriam, Frank Finley, 1865-; Neylan, John Francis, 1885-1960.; Olson, Culbert Levy, 1876-; O'Toole, John J.; Page, Charles R.; Requa, Mark Lawrence, 1866-1937.; Riley, Ray L., 1874-; Robinson, Elmer E., 1894-1982.; Rolph, James.; Searls, Robert M.; Shelley, John F., 1905-; Short, Frank H. (Frank Hamilton), 1862-1920.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Smith, Paul Clifford.; Strauss, Joseph Baermann, 1870-1938.; Thompson, Gordon.; Uhl, Adolph.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Weinberger, Caspar W.; Welch, Richard Joseph, 1869-1949.; Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1875-1949.; Willis, Bailey, 1857-1949.; Wilkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Works, John Downey, 1847-1928.; American Life Convention.; Committee for Constitutional Government.; Griffenhagen and Associates.; Republican Party.; Sigma Nu Fraternity.; Stanford University.; State Bar of California.; Primaries.; Golden Gate Bridge (Calif.); California--Politics and government--1850-1950.; San Francisco (Calif.)--Earthquake, 1906.; Maps.; Reports.; Speeches.
Series Description
- Series A. Political, 1906-1953
  This series was originally arranged by subject in more or less chronological order with a large section of overlapping material at the end representing an addition to the original gift. All correspondence has now been separated and rearranged:
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence Out (by FVK or secretary)
    Is in strictly chronological order by year, month and day. Where more than one letter for a particular date appears, these are in alphabetical order by addressee.
  - Subseries 2. Correspondence In & General (not written by FVK)
    Is arranged alphabetically by the name of the sender. Where there is more than one letter by any one person, these are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 3. Reference Material
    Includes clippings, circular letters, political hand bills, annotated copies of government documents, printed material, etc. and has been kept under the original subject headings and arranged in roughly chronological order by the earliest year date of the subject folder or group of folders. The material within each subject folder or folders is in chronological order by year, month and day. There are eight oversize scrapbooks at the end of this series.
- Series B. San Francisco Charter, 1930-1953
  This series was originally part of the former and arranged in the same manner. The new arrangement is the same for all three Subseries (Correspondence In, Out, & General, and Reference). Reference uses the original subject headings and is in the original order. Material within each folder is roughly chronological. Two oversize clipping books are found at the end of this series.
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence Out
  - Subseries 2. Correspondence In & General
  - Subseries 3. Reference Material
- Series C. Interim Committee of Twenty-Five (State Organization, 1936-1945)
  This series is almost exactly in the original subject order and with the same general subject headings. Changes may be seen by looking at the old register. Partial lists of correspondents may be found in each folder or in the first folder of a series in the CORRESPONDENCE FILE (Boxes 55-59). Material within each folder of the latter section is in chronological order by year and month. An oversize clipping scrapbook is at the end of the series.
- Series D. Golden Gate Bridge, 1919-1957
  This series was found in considerable disorder. Some material had been withdrawn from the original order and arranged by "chapters" as reference material for a doctoral dissertation. The present arrangement is as close as possible to Keesling's original subject arrangement. The material within each folder is chronological by year except for some enclosures which were kept with the covering letters. Partial lists of correspondents in the front of each folder or in the first folder of a series. Three scrapbooks are at the end of this series.
- Series E. San Francisco Earthquake, 1906., Two scrapbooks.
- Series F. Stanford Material
  This material was withdrawn from Series A. and put together as a separate series in a subject arrangement.
Container List
- Series A. Political, 1906-1953
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence Out (by FVK or secretary)
    - 1907 - 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1910 - 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1915, Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1915, July - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1916, Jan. - Mar. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1916, Apr. - May (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1916, June - July (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1916, Aug. - Sept. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1916, Oct. - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1917 - 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1924, Jan. - Apr. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1924, May - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1925 - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1929 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1933 - 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1935 - 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1937 - 1938 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1939 - 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1942 - 1943 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1944 - 1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1946 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1947 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 1949 - 1950 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 1951 - 1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - n.d. and fragments (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 2. Correspondence In & General (not written by FVK)
    - A (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Agnew, F.J. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ba - Be (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Bi - Br (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Booth, W.H. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Bu (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ca (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - California (government, etc.) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Carrere, J.F. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ce - Cl (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Co (including Coolidge - 2 tls) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Coolidge Clubs (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Cr - Cu (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - D (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - E (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - F (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - G (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Ha (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Hammond, Harry (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - He - Hoo (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Hor - I (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Hughes' Visit (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - J (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - K (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - La - Let (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Lapham, R.D. (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Lev - Ly (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Mc - Mac (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Ma (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Me - Mi (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Mo - My (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Mott, J.G. (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - N - O (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - P - Q (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Ra - Re (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Republican Coms. -- National (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Republican Coms. -- California State (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Republican Coms. -- California State Central Com. (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Republican Coms. -- No. California and Congressional Districts (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Republican Coms. -- California Counties (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Republican Coms. -- Cities and Districts (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Ri - Ry (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Sa - Sk (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - San Francisco A - C (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - San Francisco D - W (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Sigma Nu Fraternity (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Sl - Sw (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - T - U - V (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - United Service Organizations (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Wa - We (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Wh - Wy (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Y - Z (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Unknown and Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Subseries 3. Reference Material
    - Judge Cooper Campaign, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - National Guard Rehabilitation, 1907 - 1909 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Jason Rolph and Municipal Conf., 1908 - 1911 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - Hetch Hetchy (beginning), 1908 - 1915, 1923, 1931 - 1932 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Keesling Campaign for Lt. Gov., 1910 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Municipal Conference, 1911 - 1914 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Bar Association of San Francisco, 1912 - 1932 (Box 9, Folder 86)
      - early history, grievance com., library legislative activities, preparedness parade
    - Keesling for Governor Campaign, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - State Republican Com., 1914 -1917 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Miscellaneous, 1914 - 1922 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Mexico, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - National Republican, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Non-Partisan Program (Johnson), Campaign Against, 1915 - 1916 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Republican Presidential Primary, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 93)
      - includes minutes of State Conference of Republicans, Mar. 4 and campaign
    - Republican Presidential Campaign, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 94)
      - Primary and Pre-National Convention
    - Republican Campaign, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 95)
      - Primary and pre-National Convention
    - Republican Campaign 1916 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Hughes for President Campaign (includes Hotel Virginia incident), 1916 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Hughes for President Campaign, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Hiram Johnson -- Hughes Campaign, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - Hiram Johnson--subsequent to 19 16 and Hughes Campaign (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Booth (Willis) for Senate 1916 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Communism, Communitsts, and Radicals (1 of 4) 1916 - 1934 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Communism, Communitsts, and Radicals (2 of 4) 1935 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Communism, Communitsts, and Radicals (3 of 4) 1936 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Communism, Communitsts, and Radicals (4 of 4) 1937 -1944, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Liberty Loans 1st 1917 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Liberty Loans, 2nd and 3rd (etc.), 1917 - 1918 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - World War I, 1914 - 1922 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - Labor General, (1 of 2), 1917 - 1944 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - Labor General, (2 of 2), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - General Election-- Hoover, Johnson, Harding, Coolidge 1920 (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - Recall Police Judges -- Sullivan and Oppenheim 1921 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - California -- Miscellaneous 1921 - 1924 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - Southern Pacific and Central Pacific Railroads Separation, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - State Water and Power Act -- Hoover Dam 1922 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - Republican National Com., 1923 - 1924 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - Warren G. Harding--World Court and Death, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Coolidge (1917 - 1928) Campaign, 1 of 2, 1923 - 1924 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Coolidge (1917 - 1928) Campaign, 1 of 2, 1923 - 1924 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - State Bar of California, creation and organization 1923 - 1925, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - State Campaign, 1925 - 1926 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Aviation, 1925 - 1942 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Port of San Francisco, 1926 - 1933 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - Herbert C. Hoover Presidential Campaigns, 1927 - 1932 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Economic General: National Administration, 1927 - 1935 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - State and Municipal, 1929 - 1930 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Philippine Independence, 1916, 1929 - 1933 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Fitts for Governor, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Direct Primary California and Primary Election Law, 1 of 2, `1930 - 1934, some 1916 - 1922, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - Direct Primary California and Primary Election Law, 2 of 2, 1935 - 1936 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - State Campaign, 1931 - 1932 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Municipal Campaign--Rossi, Uhl, Byington, O'Toole 1931 - 1932 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Constitution of U.S. and Treaties, 1931 - 1953 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - Citizens Reconstruction Organization (California), 1932, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - N.R.A. 1933 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - N.R.A. 1934 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - N.R.A. 1935, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Public School Campaign (Bonds), 1933 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - National Administration, 1933 - 1937 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - National Administration, 1938 - 1944, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - State Campaign -- Merriam, C.C. Young, U. Sinclair, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Herbert Fleischhacker and Family, 1934 - 1940 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Municipal Campaign -- Judges and Rossi 1935 - 1938 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Legislation -- Real Estate Tax Offset Date, 1935 - 1940 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - Presidential Campaign, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 145)
    - California State Campaign -- Levy, Olson, Merriam, 1936 - 1938 (Box 16, Folder 146)
    - Supreme Court Bill, 1937, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Legislation -- Real Estate Tax Offset Data, etc. 1937 - 1939 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - New Deal -- Roosevelt Administration, 1937 - 1947 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Philip Bancroft for U.S. Senator and Contra Costa Company judge, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Levey for Congress, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Initiative Legislation, etc., 1938 - 1947 (Box 17, Folder 152)
    - Golden Gate Exposition, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 153)
    - "Ham and Eggs" -- Thursday 1939 (Box 17, Folder 154)
    - San Francisco Municipal Campaign and State Campaign Measures, 1939 - 1940, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 155)
    - Presidential Campaign, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Presidential Campaign, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - Legislation -- Economy Bloc, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 158)
    - Legislation -- Bills, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 159)
    - Mayoralty Campaign -- S.F., 1940 - 1943 (Box 18, Folder 160)
    - World War II, 1940 - 1941 (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - World War II, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - World War II, 1943 - 1944 (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - World War II, 1945 - 1949 (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - U.S.O., general, 1941 - 1944 (Box 18, Folder 165)
    - Insurance Legislation, 1941, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - U.S.O. Council, 1942 - 1944 (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Civilian Advisory Council -- Navy, 1942 - 1946 (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - Market Street Railway, 1942 - 1944 (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - Municipal, 1 of 2, 1942, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - Municipal, 2 of 2, 1942, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - Legislation, 1942 - 1946 (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - State, County, and Congressional -- Kenny, Warren, Houser, Rolph, 1942, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 173)
    - National Campaign, 1943 - 1946 (Box 20, Folder 174)
    - Labor, 1943 - 1946 (Box 20, Folder 175)
    - Post-War (plans, etc.), 1 of 2, 1943 - 1947 (Box 20, Folder 176)
    - Post-War (plans, etc.), 2 of 2, 1943 - 1947 (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - Political and Election Matters, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - Roger D. Lapham, mayor, 1944 - 1945 (Box 20, Folder 179)
    - Charter Revision Commission, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - Charter Revision Commission, 1945 - 1948, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 181)
    - California, including Primary Election Law, 1944 - 1950 (Box 21, Folder 182)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Council, 1 of 2, 1944 - 1947 (Box 21, Folder 183)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Council, 2 of 2, 1944 - 1947 (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - Municipal Campaign, etc., 1944 - 1946 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - Chronicle Forum, Sept. 1945 (Box 21, Folder 186)
    - Insurance Legislation, 1945 - 1946 (Box 22, Folder 187)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Council, Inc. minutes, 1945 - 1947 (Box 22, Folder 188)
    - Fair Employment Practices Commission and Fraternities, 1945 - 1952 (Box 22, Folder 189)
    - Communism -- Russia, 1945 - 1947 (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - Communism, Socialism and the Welfare State, 1945 - 1947 (Box 22, Folder 191)